

#### **SUMMARY**

Accomplished product leader with 12+ years of experience delivering impactful solutions across enterprise SaaS and consumer-facing apps. Co-founded a startup that achieved six-figure revenue and engaged 50,000+ users. Led a B2B2C EdTech platform redesign, increasing active users by 116% and boosting NPS by 5 points. Established a design system used by 30+ Agile team members and developed accessible, WCAG AA-compliant solutions through extensive user research. A skilled mentor and team leader, driving collaboration and skill growth.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS**

- Design Thinking - Interaction Design - Product Vision Setting - Stakeholder Management

User Research
Design System
Agile Methodologies
Team Leadership

Usability Testing
O to 1 Product Design
HTML / CSS / JS
Mentorship / Coaching

- Accessibility (WCAG) - End-to-End Product Development - Entrepreneurship - Cross-functional Collaboration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Carbon Direct — Seattle, WA (Remote)

December 2023 - August 2024

### Senior Product Designer

Climate tech startup delivering corporate sustainability solutions through SaaS platform and ESG advisory services to governments and Fortune 500 companies worldwide.

- Produced designs (using Miro, Figma) for dashboards, Al-driven data workflows and reporting tools driving \$750K in new revenue and 15% increase in workflow efficiency.
- Led a Design Sprint, collaborating with SMEs to uncover opportunities for a new product vertical, generating praised levels of collaboration and team building.
- Executed extensive UX research (using Dovetail, Tableau, and DataDog) to uncover customer needs and pain points related to data collection and processing, and GHG reporting.
- Enhanced design culture by implementing structured design hand-offs and QC processes.

# Mentor Collective — Boston, MA (Remote)

April 2021 - September 2023

## Senior Product Designer

EdTech startup offering a SaaS platform and personalized support to help bridge the equity gap in higher education, serving 2 million users across 200+ institutions in the U.S.

- Led design overhaul of a B2B2C SaaS platform, collaborating cross-functionally to deliver responsive, WCAG AA-compliant solutions, boosting MAU by 116% and NPS by 5 points.
- Implemented and maintained a company-wide design system adopted by 30+ team members across three product teams, ensuring consistency and reducing redundancy in design output.
- Orchestrated UX research (40+ interviews, 20+ workshops) leveraging Pendo.io and Dovetail.
- Delivered end-to-end design solutions using Miro and Figma and collaborated with remote-first, globally distributed Agile teams to launch 7 major product features.
- Mentored 2 designers and 5 cross-functional team members through workshops and structured learning initiatives.

# Mograph Mentor — Sarasota, FL (Remote)

January 2019 - April 2022

# Co-Founder & Chief of Product

Online school empowering 50,000 motion designers globally to grow their career through group mentorship and specialized courses.

- Headed end-to-end development of a B2C learning platform, integrating a marketing website, on-demand courses, and live group mentoring.
- Generated six-figure annual revenue within three years, wearing many hats and leveraging expertise in product management, design, development, and marketing.
- Managed a cross-functional team of 7, driving the go-to-market strategy for 15 new offerings, accelerating time-to-market and improving product launch efficiency.

#### **Mathieu Fortune**

Raleigh, North Carolina | Linkedin | Portfolio | +1786 779 6144 | pro.mathieu.fortune@gmail.com

Inventive Format — Miami, FL

August 2018 - July 2022

# Founder & Senior Design Consultant

Boutique design studio providing strategic and technical solutions for SMBs and startups.

- Executed the design and development of 20+ projects, from marketing landing pages to e-commerce portals contributing to an estimated \$700K in client's revenue.
- Delivered strategic guidance and execution on product direction and brand identity, including logo design, visual identity systems, and market positioning.

**Bakerly** — Miami, FL

February 2018 - January 2019

### **Product Designer**

- Spearheaded UX research, design, and implementation of e-commerce solutions, creating a direct-to-consumer sales channel that expanded revenue potential.
- Developed and optimized main marketing website, increasing site performance by an estimated 20%, while enhancing SEO.
- Contributed to packaging design for 5 new product offerings, using Adobe Creative Suite.

Self-employed — Remote

January 2017 - January 2018

# **UX & UI Developer**

• Integrated into Agile teams as UX designer and front-end developer, streamlining workflows, filling skill gaps, and boosting productivity, resulting in accelerated project timelines.

1001Pharmacies — Montpellier, France

January 2015 - January 2017

# **UX Designer & Front-end Developer**

- Pioneered the UX practice for a web and mobile e-commerce marketplace, introducing workshops on user research methods like card sorting, personas, and journey mapping.
- Collaborated extensively with marketers as a Front-End Developer to implement 10+ landing pages and tracking solutions, setting up A/B testing tools for continuous optimization.

<u>Publika</u> — Montpellier, France

January 2012 - January 2015

# **UI Developer**

- Led the front-end development of an in-house CMS platform used by 30+ clients.
- Partnered with digital marketers to implement SEO best practices across client projects.
- Completed over 60 successful web and mobile projects for SMEs and individuals, contributing to improved client satisfaction and business outcomes.

**EDUCATION** 

Linkedin Learning Issued 2024

**Aha! Product Management Professional Certificate** 

<u>Linkedin Learning</u> Issued 2024

Atlassian Agile Project Management Certificate

Scopyleft Issued 2016

Lean Startup & Running Lean Training

Koudetat Family Issued 2015

**Growth Hacking Certificate** 

Objectif 3W Issued 2012

Associate Degree, Web Design and Development